<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Propositions for general land-banks</title>
            <author>Thomas, Dalby, Sir.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1695</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 12 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 3 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A64546</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing T963</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R219260</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99830755</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99830755</idno>
            <idno type="VID">35209</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A64546)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 35209)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2082:07)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Propositions for general land-banks</title>
                  <author>Thomas, Dalby, Sir.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([2] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1695]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Signed on p. [2]: Dalby Thomas.</note>
                  <note>Imprint from Wing.</note>
                  <note>Marginal notes.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the Goldsmiths' Company Library, University of London.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Land banks --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2008-12</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-02</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-12</date>
            <label>Taryn Hakala</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-12</date>
            <label>Taryn Hakala</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="proposition">
            <pb facs="tcp:35209:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:35209:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>PROPOSITIONS FOR General Land-Banks.</head>
            <p>THAT BANKS under Money'd-Directors will not anſwer the ends of the Land<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed-men, <note place="margin">Money-Banks not National.</note> is prov'd by the Bank of <hi>England,</hi> nor will the ſame be effectual in the hands of a few, (even of the Landed Gentlemen) becauſe Self-intereſt is inceſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſantly whiſpering.</p>
            <p>Such Banks therefore deſerve the preference, whoſe proſpect is the greateſt for the general Good, and ſhall deny none (who are willing) to partake.</p>
            <p>Land (and that only) is the immoveable in place, <note place="margin">Land-Banks are Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tional.</note> and durable Eſtate of the Kingdom, and the <hi>primum Mobile</hi> of all things therein, which feels the jarrings of all other Wheels.</p>
            <p>Numbers of Traders will increaſe Traffick, <note place="margin">Landed-mens advan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tage to increaſe Trade, and lower Intereſt.</note> with the Productions of the Earth, and Manu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>factures, as alſo the Values; which will enable the Tenants to give the better Rents; but theſe are checked by the Scarcity and high Intereſts of Money, or a <hi>Medium</hi> as uſeful to promote the Commerce, which Obſtacles, 'tis therefore the Landed-men's Intereſt, (and is, and ought to be in their power) to remove, and to make the People eaſy.</p>
            <p>On the contrary, <note place="margin">Money'd mens In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tereſt oppoſite to Landed-men and Trade.</note> 'tis the Purſe-men's Profit to monopolize Trade, and to keep Money, and all <hi>Mediums</hi> ſcarce, and the Uſury high; which is a quite oppoſite Intereſt, oppreſſive to the People, and deſtructive to Traffick.</p>
            <p>'Tis the Landed-men who pay the <hi>Great</hi> Taxes, <note place="margin">Land pays the <hi>Great</hi> Taxes which Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney'd-men evade.</note> and feel the Burthens of the reſt, whilſt the Money'd-men tower up Eſtates, ſhelt'ring, and hugging themſelves in Concealments, and ſubtile Evaſions.</p>
            <p>Wherefore, <note place="margin">Banks-Credit ought to be on Lands.</note> as ſafe Banks will (certainly) have vaſt Credit, ſo the ſame ought to be founded on that firm Security of Lands, and always lodged in the Hands of the Poſſeſſors, whoſe Intereſt will (ever) guide them to the <hi>Commune Bonum</hi> of the Kingdom.</p>
            <div type="part">
               <head>The Method of Eſtabliſhing theſe Banks, may be, <hi>viz.</hi>
               </head>
               <p n="1">I. <note place="margin">Funds not to exceed ¼ of the yearly Rent, and are advantagi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous to Eſtates en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tail'd.</note> That the Poſſeſſors of Lands (tho' entail'd) be permitted to oblige their Lands for payment, as far as five Shillings in the Pound of the Rents <hi>per Annum,</hi> and the Bank-profits to attend the Inheritance. Becauſe,
<list>
                     <item>1. To determine Titles by Bank-Directors, will be Arbitrary, Tedious, and Uncer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain.</item>
                     <item>2. No Prejudice can befal the Heirs, as will preſently appear.</item>
                     <item>3. Abundance of Worthy Gentlemen, of great Eſtates in Land, will be ſecluded the intended Bank-benefits; and both the Banks and Common People will ſuffer much through the want of their Aſſiſtance.</item>
                     <item>4. If ought can be call'd Riſque, the Poſſeſſors will bear it, by advancing their Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney, which the next Heirs will enjoy with their Lands.</item>
                     <item>5. The Profits of the Bank ought to attend the Inheritance, that the Bank-manage<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment may always be in the Landed-men.</item>
                  </list>
               </p>
               <p n="2">II. <note place="margin">Bank-Stocks to be four Years Subſcrip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion certain, and ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven Years more for Security of Credi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors.</note> That every Sum ſubſcribed be divided into eleven Annual Payments; one Payment to be made at the Subſcription, and the ſame to be repeated for three more ſucceſſive Years, which will be four Years payments for a Stock to circulate the Bank-Bills, and the reſt to attend the yearly Demands of the Directors to make good the Bank-Credit, if occaſion ſhould be, which is not (at all) probable.</p>
               <p n="3">III. <note place="margin">No other Dividends than out of the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fits, reſerving the firſt four Years Stock.</note> That no Dividend be iſſu'd of more than the neat Profits, reſerving the firſt four Payments for the Bank-Stock, which will give the more ſure Credit to the Banks, and be ſo much clear Benefit to the next Heirs; and the Poſſeſſors (beſides the Bank-profits) will be alſo encouraged, in hope to out-live the few Years their Eſtates will be engaged for.</p>
               <p n="4">IV. <note place="margin">
                     <hi>London</hi> and County-Banks.</note> That one Land-Bank be in <hi>London,</hi> and branched into the moſt trading Parts of <hi>England,</hi> or each County to manage their own Banks; every of which to have ſafe Repoſitories for Goods pledged, or for ſale.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>OR TH<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>S, <hi>Viz.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>If a Fund of  <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                     <desc> _____ </desc>
                  </gap>  in the Pound Rents for  <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                     <desc> _____ </desc>
                  </gap>  years be raiſed by Parliament, <note place="margin">Land-Banks by a Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liamentary Fund.</note> and paid into the Banks without Charge, and managed by Directors choſen by Parliament, either way will create Banks alike beneficial; and if one, or the other were on foot, the Landed mens Profits would prevent their ever declining, and as ſoon advance Taxes, as will be required.</p>
               <pb facs="tcp:35209:2"/>
               <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                  <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb facs="tcp:35209:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                  <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb facs="tcp:35209:3"/>
               <p>As, <note place="margin">Taxes raiſed by a Land-Bank. Two Millions by Exciſe on Salt at 7 <hi>per Cent.</hi> Intereſt.</note> admit two Millions demanded on a Parliamentary Fund by Exciſe on Salt, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> at 7 <hi>per Cent.</hi> Intereſt, and the Banks Income by Land ſettl'd, be but 200000 <hi>
                     <abbr>l.</abbr> per. Annum,</hi> and Tal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lies or Bills made of 50 <abbr>
                     <hi>l.</hi>
                  </abbr> or 100 <abbr>
                     <hi>l.</hi>
                  </abbr> each, for the ſaid two Millions at 7 <hi>per Cent.</hi> Intereſt; the Banks having power to haſten the payments of the Tallies, as their Bank-Stocks and Credit will admit, more Tallies would be call'd in, than the Owners would willingly bring, and be as current as any Bank-Bills whatſoever.</p>
               <p>But to advance the Banks Credit, <note place="margin">To pay off 1/10 part yearly.</note> That Fund for the 7 <hi>per Cent.</hi> Intereſt of the Two Mil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lions may be ſo enlarged, as one tenth part of the ſaid Two Millions to be paid off yearly.</p>
               <p>
                  <table>
                     <row>
                        <cell>And if the Banks receive out of the ſaid Exciſe-Fund (beſides that Intereſt) the yearly Sum (towards diſcharge of the Principal of the ſaid Two Mil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lions) of</cell>
                        <cell>
                           <abbr>
                              <hi>l.</hi>
                           </abbr> 200,000</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>And that no more Annual Income by Lands ſetled for the Banks Stocks (as cannot be imagined but that abundantly more will undoubtedly be ſubſcribed) than</cell>
                        <cell>200,000</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>The Banks will then receive <hi>per Annum</hi>
                        </cell>
                        <cell role="total">400,000</cell>
                     </row>
                  </table>
               </p>
               <p>Beſides the 7 <hi>per Cent.</hi> Intereſt of thoſe Tallies they ſhall annually (by their own Stock) call in from the People.</p>
               <p>Conſequently all the Tallies for the Two Millions will be paid off to the People in leſs than five years without the aſſiſtance of the Bank-Credit, <note place="margin">The two Millions paid off in leſs than five Years.</note> whereby the Banks will have the certain benefits of that 7 <hi>per Cent.</hi> for their Monies advanced, until ſatisfied to them by the Nation.</p>
               <p>For which Reaſons, <note place="margin">Banks protected by <hi>King, Lords,</hi> and <hi>Commons.</hi>
                  </note> Theſe Bank-Bills or Tallies with the Intereſt of 7 <hi>per Cent.</hi> will be more acceptable in all Payments, and more like to be paid off on demand, than any other Sett of Bank-Bills whatſoever: And the rather, Becauſe ſuch Land-Banks cannot fail of the protection of the <hi>King, Lords</hi> and <hi>Commons,</hi> theſe being entirely in the Intereſt of the Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion; therefore greater or more ſecure Credit cannot be wiſhed for.</p>
               <p>'Twill be the advantage of ſuch Banks to lend Money at eaſy Rates on Goods depoſited, <note place="margin">Manufactur'd Goods ſold at beſt Prices, and the Owners freed from being impos'd on by the preſent Factors.</note> and become Factors thereof, to ſell thoſe at beſt Prices, and thereby free the Owners from being impoſed on (as is not ſeldom done) by the preſent Factors, through the want of Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney for the ſaid Owners neceſſary Occaſions, which often urges untimely Sales of the Manu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>factures at under Rates, whereby the Productions of the Earth (whereof thoſe are made) do alſo fall low, and diſable the Tenant in their Dues to their Landlords, who are (at <hi>Bot<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tom</hi>) the Loſers; and <hi>è Conversô,</hi> the more the Manufactures yield, the higher will be the Products of the Earth, as is evident by the riſe of the Wool on the ſudden advance of the Woollen Manufactures.</p>
               <p>Managers of Land-Banks will (contrary to Money-Banks) ſtudy hard to ſink Intereſt; Becauſe, as that falls, Land riſes, both in Rents, and in Sales; for the uſe of Money is equally conſidered by the Farmers, and Makers of, and Dealers in, Manufactures, as if the like Tax were put on their Stocks; And as high Intereſt abates, leſs Taxes will be needful to pay that Intereſt of Taxes.</p>
               <p>In ſum, <note place="margin">Land-Banks will do the moſt good.</note> Theſe Banks will be capable of doing (at leaſt) as much good as any other Banks can pretend to, and more good than can be eaſily expreſſed (in ſo ſmall a Treatiſe) or rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dily thought of; and can injure none, ſave in diſappointing the Uſurers from devouring the Labours of the beſt Deſigning, and moſt Induſtrious of the People.</p>
               <p>Much more might be ſaid; but not to reflect; The preſent Intent is to repeat and pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mote what has been formerly <hi>by me</hi> made publick, as moſt National and Practical; And whether theſe Methods are (or are not) approved for raiſing Taxes this Year, 'tis heartily wiſhed, that ſuch a liberty by Law be given for all Landed-men (by Bank-credit) to im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prove their Eſtates (and for being moſt National under their management); and alſo, That any Perſons who now do (or hereafter ſhall) join in the ſetling ſafe Banks, may be incorporated under proper Limitations; For certainly, the greater the number of ſuch Banks, the better will it be for the Nation in general, and for the Landed-men in particular: Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>commending (with ſubmiſſion) to the obſervation of our Legiſlators, to oblige thoſe by Law to perform their Pretences, <note place="margin">Specious Pretenders to be oblig'd to per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>form their Promiſes.</note> who have made (or ſhall make) ſpecious Inſinuations and Promiſes to lend Money at low Intereſt; and not be ſuffered to purchaſe Lands, leaſt they leſſen the number of the Countrey Gentry (by engroſſing their Lands) as was formerly done by the Abbies, Priories and Nunneries; and that a due care be had to prevent encouraging the Monopolizing (eſpecially of Foreign) Commodities conſumeable in <hi>England.</hi> And that Stock-jobbings, and all voluntary Diminutions out of the Capital be totally ſuppreſſed. And no Dividend admitted, ſave what ſhall ariſe out of the certain Profits of the Banks.</p>
               <p>If the Readers find all (or ought herein) for the Kingdom's Advantage, and will pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mote the ſame, I ſhall think my Pains well ſpent for the common good of the Nation, in general; and that my good Intentions may meet with a favourable Conſtruction, is hoped for. By</p>
               <closer>
                  <signed>Dalby Thomas.</signed>
               </closer>
               <pb facs="tcp:35209:3"/>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
